{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which gas is mainly responsible for the greenhouse effect?",
      "answers": ["CO2", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which technology is used to convert solar energy into electrical energy?",
      "answers": ["Solar panels", "Generators", "Steam turbines", "Nuclear reactors"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which effect describes the ability of a material to convert light into electrical energy?",
      "answers": ["Photovoltaic effect", "Hall effect", "Piezoelectric effect", "Thermoelectric effect"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which is not a fossil fuel?",
      "answers": ["Solar energy", "Petroleum", "Coal", "Uranium"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Where were the first solar cells used?",
      "answers": ["To power telephone amplifiers", "To drive machines", "In space exploration", "To heat water"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Which process releases more energy?",
      "answers": ["Nuclear fusion", "Coal combustion", "Nuclear fission", "Gas combustion"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "When was the first power plant in Germany established?",
      "answers": ["1904", "1906", "1886", "1772"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which power plants can be regulated within seconds?",
      "answers": ["Pumped storage power plants", "Nuclear power plants", "Coal power plants", "Wind power plants"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "What is the purpose of a power-saving mode in a microcontroller?",
      "answers": ["Minimizing power consumption", "Maximizing performance", "Increasing response speed", "Improving connectivity"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following methods does not necessarily help reduce the power consumption of a microcontroller?",
      "answers": ["Increasing the clock frequency", "Using low-power sleep modes", "Reducing operating voltage", "Disabling unnecessary peripherals"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "What is the main disadvantage of power-saving modes in microcontrollers?",
      "answers": ["Reduced performance", "Increased operational costs", "Increased environmental impact", "Decreased security"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Which metal conducts electricity the best?",
      "answers": ["Aluminum", "Silver", "Copper", "Iron"],
      "correctAnswer": 1,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "What unit is used to measure the power of a device?",
      "answers": ["Watt", "Volt", "Kilowatt-hour", "Ohm"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "Which is NOT a programming language?",
      "answers": ["HTTP", "PHP", "Java", "Python"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What does HTTP stand for?",
      "answers": ["Hypertext Transfer Protocol", "Hybrid Talk To Protocol", "Human Telephone Traffic Protocol", "World Wide Web"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "What type of programming language is Java?",
      "answers": ["A compiled language", "An interpreted language", "A scripting language", "A markup language"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "What is a loop in programming?",
      "answers": ["An instruction that repeats a set number of times", "A section of code that performs a specific task", "A condition to perform a specific operation", "A function that reads and loads data from a file"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "What is \"JavaScript\"?",
      "answers": ["A client-side scripting language", "A server-side programming language", "A low-level programming language", "An object-oriented programming language"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is \"Python\" in computing?",
      "answers": ["A programming language", "A dangerous virus", "A greeting phrase", "A security program"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which hash function is used in computers?",
      "answers": ["SHA-256", "ASCII", "Base64", "AES"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "Which codes are used to detect errors in data transmission?",
      "answers": ["Checksums", "Binary code", "Morse code", "QR code"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "Which routing protocol is commonly used in large computer networks such as the Internet?",
      "answers": ["BGP (Border Gateway Protocol)", "DNS (Domain Name System)", "HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol)", "ARP (Address Resolution Protocol)"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "What type of algorithm is used to find the shortest path between two points in a graph?",
      "answers": ["Dijkstra's algorithm", "Breadth-First Search", "Depth-First Search", "Euclidean algorithm"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "What term describes programming languages that are directly translated into machine code using a compiler?",
      "answers": ["Compiled", "Transpiled", "Interpreted", "Synthesized"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "Who handles the execution of interpreted programming languages?",
      "answers": ["Virtual machines", "Physical machines", "Random Access Memory (RAM)", "Interpreted languages are not executed"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "Why is a compiled language more energy-efficient than an interpreted language?",
      "answers": ["The executable code runs directly on the CPU without further translation", "It handles memory better", "It uses AI for efficient execution", "The produced bytecode is platform-independent and thus more efficient"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "How can you recognize a secure connection?",
      "answers": ["By the green padlock next to the address bar", "By the siteâ€™s imprint", "By the visual design of the site", "By the cookie banner"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "Which of the following passwords is the most secure?",
      "answers": ["y!RkmTh%GRk8", "SuPeRsEcUrEpAsSwOrD", "12345678", "P1$$w0r+"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "What does the term \"malware\" mean?",
      "answers": ["Malicious software", "Drawing programs, such as Paint", "Software that slows down the PC", "Software that works intermittently"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "How long does it take an average computer to guess a password with 8 characters?",
      "answers": ["32 seconds", "16 hours", "8 minutes", "1 minute"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "What does the term \"Ransomware\" stand for?",
      "answers": ["Malware that encrypts all data and extorts the owner", "Program that performs random actions", "Malware that changes the user's background image", "Program that causes the computer to crash"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "What is the best format for a secure password?",
      "answers": ["A combination of uppercase and lowercase letters", "A word from the dictionary", "Your birthdate", "Your pet's name"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "What is a phishing attack?",
      "answers": ["A scam to steal data via fraudulent emails or websites", "An online fishing game", "A type of virus that spreads through social media", "A method to hack a computer via a wireless connection"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "What is a firewall?",
      "answers": ["A device that controls network traffic to protect a network", "A barrier to stop a fire in a building", "A type of virus that spreads via email attachments", "A method to encrypt sensitive data"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "What is a \"Man-in-the-Middle\" attack?",
      "answers": ["An attack where a hacker intercepts and manipulates communication between two parties", "An attack where a hacker creates a fake website", "An attack where a hacker logs into a network and steals data", "An attack where a hacker installs malware on a system"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "What is \"Two-Factor Authentication\"?",
      "answers": ["A method to verify a user's identity in two ways", "A method to record suspicious activities in two ways", "A method to use two physical tokens for user identification", "A method where a system is automatically updated and patched"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "What is \"Reverse Engineering\" in cybersecurity?",
      "answers": ["A technique to analyze and understand existing code", "A method to check a website for vulnerabilities", "An attack to establish a connection to the victim's system", "A method to create malware code"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "What is \"Social Engineering\" in cybersecurity?",
      "answers": ["A method that exploits human weaknesses", "A method to create malware code", "A method to crack passwords", "An attack to establish a connection to the victim's system"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation SSL stand for in web security?",
      "answers": ["Secure Socket Layer", "System Socket Language", "System Security Language", "Secure Server Link"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "When is a replay attack possible?",
      "answers": ["When the key is reused", "When the recipient does not receive the message", "When multiple transmission errors occur", "When no error correction is used"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "What does an attacker attempt to manipulate in a BGP Hijacking attack?",
      "answers": ["Routing information", "Email security", "Position of satellites", "Internet connection speed"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "What is the binary representation of the instruction \"ret\" (Hexadecimal: c3)?",
      "answers": ["11000011", "10010110", "11110000", "00000001"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "What is a switch in a network?",
      "answers": ["A device that controls network traffic", "A device that routes data between different networks", "A device that enables internet access via a modem", "A device that establishes wireless connections between devices"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "What is a \"Router\" in a network?",
      "answers": ["A device that connects two or more networks", "A device that transmits data packets within a network", "A device that monitors and regulates network traffic within a network", "A device that enables wireless connections in a network"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "Which technology is used to wirelessly exchange data between devices?",
      "answers": ["Bluetooth", "HDMI", "USB", "Ethernet"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "What type of component is a microcontroller?",
      "answers": ["Active component", "Passive component", "Electromechanical component", "Semiconductor component"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "Which semiconductor element is most commonly used in technology?",
      "answers": ["Silicon", "Indium", "Arsenic", "Gallium"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "How much memory does an instruction occupy in a 64-bit system?",
      "answers": ["8 bytes", "1 byte", "2 bytes", "4 bytes"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "What is the purpose of \"Dynamic Voltage and Frequency Scaling\" (DVFS) in a computer system?",
      "answers": ["Adjustment of the processor's operating voltage and clock frequency", "Minimization of the processor's performance", "Maximization of the screen resolution", "Minimization of RAM usage"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "What is meant by QWERTZ/QWERTY?",
      "answers": ["A keyboard layout", "A mineral", "A part of the hard drive", "A WLAN network"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "question": "How many bits are in a byte?",
      "answers": ["8", "4", "12", "16"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation RAM stand for?",
      "answers": ["Random Access Memory", "Rechargeable Accumulator Module", "Remote Administration Module", "Raw Access Modifier"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "question": "Which factor most strongly influences the power consumption of a microcontroller?",
      "answers": ["Clock frequency", "Operating voltage", "Size of internal memory", "Number of I/O pins"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "question": "In which unit is electric current measured?",
      "answers": ["Ampere", "Volt", "Watt", "Ohm"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "question": "Which component of a computer executes the instructions of a program?",
      "answers": ["CPU", "PSU", "Ethernet Controller", "Mainboard"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "question": "Imagine you want to take a trip with your family and plan an excursion where you want to visit as many sights as possible. Which problem of computer science does this scenario relate to?",
      "answers": ["The Traveling Salesman Problem", "The Unit Distance Problem", "The Gravity Problem", "The Knapsack Problem"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "question": "How does the so-called Greedy algorithm get its name?",
      "answers": ["Only the biggest gain counts when making a decision", "Only greedy people use it", "It was developed by Edwin Greedy as an optimization method", "The name was chosen randomly"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "question": "The Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP) is a widespread phenomenon outside of computer science as well. Do you have an idea where it occurs in your everyday life?",
      "answers": ["All mentioned areas", "In package delivery", "In creating schedules", "In building the mobile network"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation TSP stand for in computer science?",
      "answers": ["Traveling-Salesman-Problem", "Travis-Smiller-Privacy", "Talented-Student-Program", "Technical Software Problem"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 60,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation VPN stand for?",
      "answers": ["Virtual Private Network", "Virtual Personal Network", "Virtual Perimeter Network", "Virtual Public Network"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 61,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation PDF stand for?",
      "answers": ["Portable Document Format", "Post Delivery Format", "Public Document File", "Private Data File"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 62,
      "question": "What are benign hackers called?",
      "answers": ["Whitehats", "Greyhats", "Green Team", "Blackhats"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 63,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation WWW stand for?",
      "answers": ["World Wide Web", "Whenever Wherever Whatever", "World Weather Website", "Witchcraft Wizardry Workshop"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 64,
      "question": "What problem do you have to solve to get a million dollars?",
      "answers": ["Traveling Salesman Problem", "Driving Car Problem", "Internet Security Problem", "Yellow Brick Road Problem"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 65,
      "question": "In computer science, what is also called a bug?",
      "answers": ["A software error", "A defective PC", "A damaged keyboard", "A customer problem"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 66,
      "question": "What does the abbreviation LAN mean?",
      "answers": ["Local Area Network", "Long Access Network", "Limited Availability Network", "Link Access Node"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 67,
      "question": "What is a cookie?",
      "answers": ["A small text file stored by the browser on the PC", "Small images that appear in the browser", "Small windows that need to be clicked away in the browser", "Data that used to be stored on a CD"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 68,
      "question": "What is a \"Honeypot\" in cybersecurity?",
      "answers": ["A virtual machine used to distract an attacker", "A method to store data more securely in the cloud", "A tool for encrypting outgoing emails", "A type of firewall that is rarely used"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 69,
      "question": "What is the world's most popular password?",
      "answers": ["123456", "111111", "000000", "admin"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 100,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 70,
      "question": "Where does the name \"Bluetooth\" come from?",
      "answers": ["From Harald Bluetooth, a Viking king", "From the blue glowing light", "From the \"interlocking\" devices", "From the name of the inventor"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 71,
      "question": "When was the first email sent?",
      "answers": ["1971", "1852", "2002", "1994"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 400,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 72,
      "question": "What is a Denial-of-Service attack?",
      "answers": ["An attack where a hacker overwhelms a network", "An attack where a hacker manipulates a database", "An attack where a hacker remotely controls a computer", "An attack where a hacker steals data from a network"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 300,
      "topic": "Security"
    },
    {
      "id": 73,
      "question": "How did the Berlin artist Simon Weckert cause an artificial traffic jam in 2020?",
      "answers": [
        "With 99 smartphones in a handcart",
        "By having breakfast on the highway",
        "With an artwork made of e-scooters",
        "By collecting plastic bottles in the Spree"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "score": 200,
      "topic": "Fun Fact"
    }
  ]
}